コードギアス反逆のルルーシュR2 TURN 9　朱禁城　の　花嫁
TURN 9　朱禁城　の　花嫁
The Chinese Federation.
中華連邦 世界最大の人口を誇る連合国家
An alliance of nations boasting
the largest population in the world.
But the truth is that it can already
be called a weak old man.
しかし その実態はすでに老人といっていい
The symbol of this
alliance is the empress.
国家の象徴たる天子
The ruling class which control society from
her shadow has grown exceedingly tyrannical,
その地位を影であやつる支配層が
専横を極めており
while poverty and stagnation have
sapped the life from the nation's people.
人民は貧困と停滞にその活力を奪われていた
It is to this Chinese Federation that
the Black Knights have fled Japan.
日本を脱出した黒の騎士団のむかったのはこの中華連邦である
The High Eunuchs, the most powerful men
at the time, have lent the Japanese people...
時の権力者　大宦官は日本人のために 江蘇省沖
the man made island of Horai,
built for tidal power generation...
黄海にうかぶ潮力発電用の人工島 蓬莱島を貸し与えた
off the coast of Jiangsu
province in the Yellow Sea.
While this arrangement had been
worked out in advance,
事前に話がついていたとはいえ
it was only later that the political
implications of this became clear.
これが政治的にいかなる意味をもつのかは
後にわかることとなる
Asa mo yoru mo koikogarete
Morning and night, I long for you
hoshi ni naru yo kimi mamoru
I'll become a star and protect you
tatakai wa yukue shirazu
No matter where the battle may take me
ashita to kinou no kousaten de
At the intersection of tomorrow and yesterday
majiwaranai kimi to boku
You and I can't be together
ima iku yo boku wa nagareboshi
I'm a shooting star, on my way right now
sekai ga kuchihatetemo
Even if the world crumbles apart
kawaru koto no nai mono ga aru
There are things which will never change
namida wo koraete demo
Even as we bear tears in our eyes
mamorubeki mono ga bokura ni wa aru
There are things we must protect
nanman'nen nan'okunen mae kara no
A message that's been in my body
message ga tainai de
For thousands and millions of years,
uzukidasu... mayoi wa nai
Springs out... I have no reservations
narihibiku... kantan da
Roars out... It's easy
shagareta koe de... asu wo yobu
In a hoarse voice... Calling tomorrow
kizudarake no te de... kimi mamoru
With my wounded hands... I protect you
I continue to fight...
I continue to fight!
asa mo yoru mo koikogarete
Morning and night, I long for you
hoshi ni naru yo kimi mamoru
I'll become a star and protect you
tatakai wa yukue shirazu
No matter where the battle may take me
ashita to kinou no kousaten de
At the intersection of tomorrow and yesterday
majiwaranai kimi to boku
You and I can't be together
sadame wo kirisaku nagareboshi
I'm a shooting star, tearing fate apart
afureru kimi no namida boku ga ima ubaisaru
I'll take away your overflowing tears right now
A BRIDE IN THE VERMILION FORBIDDEN CITY
JAPANESE LOAN DISTRICT - HORAI ISLAND
よくみとめてくれたな中華連邦が
Man, the Chinese Federation's really giving us a lot of recognition, huh?
There was that whole bit with Sawasaki, too.
Think they're pro-Japanese?
澤崎の件もあるしさ　親日派なんじゃないの？
大宦官が？
The High Eunuchs?
朝比奈知ってるか？！
Asahina, did you hear this?
The High Eunuchs may be guys...
宦官ってのはな 男なのにここがないんだよ
but they've got no junk down here!
Tamaki, you're gonna get us in trouble
for making fun of stuff like that!
玉城！そういう茶化しかたは問題だぞ
Aw, c'mon!
だってよ
おい ナイトメアをおろすの手伝ってくれ
Hey! Can I get some help off-
loading some Knightmares?
They're already here?
もう届いたの？
インドがここまで協力的だと 何か裏でもありそうな
For India to be giving us this much cooperation,
something must be going on behind the scenes.
No, they may be surprisingly
serious about this.
いや 意外と本気かもしれない
They're trying to get their independence
from the Chinese Federation, too.
中華連邦から独立したがってるわけだし
Rakshata mentioned that, too.
ラクシャータもそんなこと言ってたな
Well, considering how they get called
the land of barbarians by the Chinese...
化外の地なんて言われちゃさあ
We've finished picking out
candidates for staff leaders.
幹部候補の人材のピックアップは終わりました
Should we station them
aboard the Ikaruga?
当面はイカルガに？
Correct. That leaves us
with the civil administrators.
そうだあとは内政担当者だが
I agree.
承知しております
Let's work with the intelligence
section and get that set up.
情報管理のセクションとあわせ構築しましょう
Now, if you'll excuse me...
では
ディートハルトは信用できるの？
Can we depend on Diethard?
咲世子さんのときみたいに独断で
He tends to act on his own,
like Sayoko that time.
To the contrary,
he's become even easier to read.
逆によみやすくなった
あの男はゼロという記号を神にしようとしている
He's trying to make Zero
a symbol of God.
Starting from there, you can guess
what actions he'll take, right?
行動はそこから推測できるだろう
Besides, he has a useful talent
for manipulating information.
それに情報操作に関しては得難い逸材だからな
うむおおよそつかんだ
Okay, that just about does it.
That just leaves the combat carrier.
あとは戦闘空母か
You're installing the Gawain's
system onto the Ikaruga, right?
イカルガにガウェインシステムをうつしたわけだな
The Shinkirō utilizes it as well.
蜃気楼にもつかったけどねえ
何しろ本体は海中からひきあげた時点でボロボロだったから
The main body looked so damaged
when we salvaged it from the water.
いっしょに沈んでいた機体は？
What about the unit
that sank with it?
ナイトギガフォートレスとかいうやつか？
The one they're calling
the Knight Giga Fortress?
私もさがしたんだけどね
I tried looking
for that myself, but...
You're serious about wanting to take down
the capital of the Chinese Federation?
本気で中華連邦の首都をおとすつもり？
侵略者にならない方法でね
In a way where we won't be
considered to be the aggressors.
If we can take down Luoyang, we clear a
lot of conditions for defeating Britannia.
洛陽さえ落とせば
ブリタニアを落とす条件はほぼクリアされる
Looks like he's all right now.
もう大丈夫みたいね
I wasn't sure what he was going to do that time.
あのときはどうなるかと思ったけど
どうした？
What's up?
教えてルルーシュ
Tell me, Lelouch.
Tell me why you came back.
どうして戻ってきてくれたの？
カレン すべてが終わったらいっしょにアッシュフォード学園に帰らないか？
Kallen... When this is all over, would you
go back to Ashford Academy with me?
俺は
I...
タバスコ
Tabasco.
How long have you been there?!
おまえ いつから？
それよりタバスコだ
It needs Tabasco, but all we have is
this Chinese spiced oil. What to do?
ここにはラー油しかない　どうしよう
それは
Um...
どうしましょう
Now what do we do?
ゼロ様！イカルガにきてください
Master Zero, please come to
the Ikaruga! We've got trouble!
たいへんなことが！
何？政略結婚？
What?
A political marriage?
Yes. I received an invitation to the ceremony
through the Sumeragi Conglomerate.
ええ皇コンツェルンをとおして
式の招待状が届いたのですけど
新婦は この中華連邦の象徴　天子様
The bride is to be the empress,
who's the symbol of the Chinese Federation.
私を友人として招きたいと
She wants me there
as her good friend.
そして新郎はブリアニア帝国第一皇子
And the groom is to be
the first prince of Britannia.
オデュッセウスとかいう人
That one they call Odysseus.
It's too soon to activate
the plan we've prepared.
用意していた計画はまにあいません
まさか大宦官が
I never thought
the High Eunuchs would...
No, this is a Britannian plot.
いや ブリタニアの仕掛けだろう
In that case, what do we do?
だとしたら 俺たちは
This is the worst possible
case for us.
最悪のケースだ
And I was going to move against
the empress before they could!
この手をうたれるまえに天子をおさえるつもりだったのに
まさかこんなに早く
I never thought that mediocre
man would move so fast!
あんな凡庸な男が
Aw, don't sweat it! It's not like we
have anything to do with Britannia!
な～にを心配してんだよ
俺たちはブリタニアとは関係ないだろ？
はあ？
We've been exiled, remember?
国外追放されたんだからさ
Um... That doesn't mean they've
excused our crimes, right?
あの 罪が許されたわけじゃないんですけど
Besides, a political marriage...
それに政略結婚ですし
中華連邦が私たちを攻撃してくる可能性だって
It's possible the Chinese
Federation might attack us.
Then what?! Are the Black Knights
a wedding gift for them?!
じゃあなにかよ！黒の騎士団は結婚の結納品がわりか？！
あら うまいこと言いますね
Actually, that's a good way to put it.
You're developing a nice,
useless talent there.
つかえない才能に満ち満ちているなあ
This is no time to sit around joking!
We're in big trouble here!
のんきこいてる場合か！
大ピンチなんだぞ これは！
Which is why...
だからさ
we're discussing it right now!
それを話してんるんだよ 今
Zero, behind this...
ゼロ この裏には
Yes. There's one other person.
ああ もうひとりいるな
険悪だった中華連邦との関係を一気に
Only one man could reverse their poor relations
with the Chinese Federation overnight...
こんな悪魔みたいな手をうったやつが
by making such a devilish move!
ブリタニアへ売り払う 天子様を
Would they dare?
Sell Her Majesty to the Britannians?!
LUOYANG - VERMILION FORBIDDEN CITY
Reception Hall
天子様は納得しておられるんでしょうか
The empress has consented
to this, hasn't she?
むこうがそう言っているからには信じるしか
That's what they said,
so we have to take their word for it.
それにこれは平和への道のひとつだし
Besides, this is one path to peace.
Right...
はあ
Let's just enjoy
ourselves as guests.
ここは招待客として 楽しみましょうよ
Suzaku! I found it!
スザク！あったあった
これだろ？おまえが言っていた　イモリの黒焼き
This is that charred newt stuff
you told me about, right?
どうやって食べるんだ？
How do I eat it?
That's just a decoration
made out of food.
これは料理の飾りだって
飾り？
Decoration?
あでも さっき似たような鳥を食べてましたよね？
But you just ate a bird like
this before, didn't you?
Bird...
You mean the Chinese phoenix?
鳥って 鳳凰？
Oh, is that what it was? I thought it was
meat, but it was made out of carrots...
そういう料理なの？お肉かと思ったら人参で
これはポテトかな？食べてもいいんだろ
Is this made out of potato?
I can eat it, can't I?
Sir Alstreim, you're getting
e-mails here in the reception hall?
アールストレーム卿 迎賓館の中ではメールをうっても
Uh-uh.
I'm memorizing this.
ううん これは記憶
Oh, that's a diary?
ああ 日記ですか
だったら記録だねえ
Then it's "recording," my dear!
Um, Lloyd, am I still
your fiancée or not?
あの 私ってまだロイドさんの婚約者なんでしょうか？
Huh? We haven't
canceled it, have we?
あれ？解消はしてないよね
Well, this is a rare sight.
めずらしいじゃない
明日の式だけ参列して 祝賀会にはこないと思ってた
I figured you would skip the celebration party
and just attend the ceremony tomorrow.
Suzaku sometimes gets mad at me and
says I should act more like a fiancé.
たまには婚約者らしいこともしろって
スザクくんに怒られちゃったから
で こちらがその対象
This young lady here
being the cause of that.
How do you do?
I'm Milly Ashford.
はじめましてミレイ アッシュフォードです
よろしく
A pleasure. I'm shocked Lloyd would
show any interest in anything human.
ロイドが人間に興味があったなんて驚いたわ
いや～成長期だから
Well, I guess I'm growing up.
こちらはカノン マルティーニ伯爵
This is Earl Kannon Maldini,
Prince Schneizel's aide-de-camp.
シュナイゼル殿下の側近
公私ともにね
In matters public and private.
えっ あ
I'm kidding.
冗談よ　シュナイゼル殿下は変わり者がお好きなの
Prince Schneizel
likes unusual things.
私も含めてね
Myself included.
神聖ブリタニア帝国宰相
Announcing the prime minister
of the Holy Britannian Empire!
Second prince
Schneizel has arrived!
シュナイゼル第二皇子様　ご到着
あっまさか ニーナ！
It can't be... Nina!
ほう弟は特定の女性はつくらなかったんだけどねえ
Ah! I never thought my younger brother
would be so steady in his choice of escorts.
Ah...
誰？あの子
Who is that girl?
Isn't she the chief of Invogue?
インヴォーグのチーフじゃない？
Yes, the prince's research team.
ああ殿下の研究チーム
She's awfully young.
ずいぶんとお若いこと
She should know her place!
身の程もしらず
Be strong.
Euphy was always quite grand.
しっかり
ユフィはいつも堂々としていたよ
Yes.
はい
It's been a while.
お久しぶりです
皇帝陛下から この地ではシュナイゼル殿下の指揮下にはいるようにと
His Majesty has ordered that
we take orders from you in this land.
ラウンズが３人もたのもしいねえ
Three of the Rounds?
How splendid! However...
ただ
何か？
What, sir?
ここは祝いの場だ
This is a celebration!
You should relax a little more!
もっとらくにしてくれないと
Understood, sir!
わかりました
スザク 学園のみんなは元気？
Suzaku, is everyone at school well?
Yeah. See for yourself.
ああほら
は～い
Hi!
ミレイちゃん！
Milly!
大宦官とシュナイゼルの間にはすでに密約が成立しています
The High Eunuchs and Prince Schneizel
have already set up a secret agreement.
婚姻と領土の割譲
Once she's married,
they'll cede our territory to them.
それにより 大宦官はブリタニアの爵位を手にいれると
He's said the High Eunuchs will
be given Britannian titles of nobility.
Titles of nobility?
They'd sell their country for that?!
爵位？地位とひきかえに国を売るか
民はどうなる？！
And what about the people?!
Death to the High Eunuchs!
大宦官 討つべし！
We need to stop this wedding,
even if it means starting the plan early.
そうだ！計画を前倒しにしてでも 婚姻をつぶす！
だがここでクーデターをおこせば ブリタニアとの戦争に
But if we stage a coup,
it'll mean war with Britannia.
平和をとるべきか それとも
Either we have to
ensure peace, or else...
しかし天子様 この男は囚人にいらぬ情けを
But, Your Majesty, this man tried to
unlawfully save a prisoner.
でも 私だって風邪をひいたらお薬をいただくのに
But... I get brought medicine
when I'm sick, so?
いえ 天子様と囚人では
There's no comparing that
prisoner with you, Your Majesty!
The banquet will be starting soon!
Do as Her Majesty commands!
もうすぐ宴がはじまるここは天子様の言うとおりにせん！
しかし 法に照らせば この男は死罪
But, if he's taken to face the law,
he'll be executed!
おかしいわ！
But, that's wrong!
That's wrong!
He was doing something good!
そんなのおかしいわ！
そのひと いいことをしたのに
え その
Well, you see...
Officer's school?
士官学校？
はい 天子様にいただいた命です
Yes. That's how I'm using the life
that you spared, Your Majesty.
少しでもお守りできるよう
I wish to protect you
in any way I can.
私もいってみたい外に
I'd like to go, too. Outside.
外？
Outside?
朱禁城の外には 海とか 学校とか
Out of the forbidden city.
To the sea, or maybe to school.
Where there's hot foods
and friends to make.
あたたかい食べ物とか 友達っていうのもあるって
わかりました
Very well, then.
え？
いずれ私が天子様を外にお連れ致しましょう
One day, I will take you out
of here, Your Majesty.
Really?!
ほんと？
救っていただいた命のお返しとして
As thanks for
your sparing my life.
ん？
外では こうやって約束するんです
We make promises like this
outside the city.
永続調和の
A promise made...
契りを
for all time.
天子様を守るべきか 平和への同盟か
The choice is either protect Her Majesty
or allow an alliance to ensure peace.
いや～本当によかった
Anyway, I'm certainly glad of this!
I'm no good at fighting.
私は争いごとは苦手でねえ
殿下皇帝陛下は婚礼には
Does His Majesty plan
to attend the wedding?
本国での宴には顔をだすと言っていましたよ
He said he would attend the
banquet back in the homeland.
The representative of
the Sumeragi Conglomerate!
皇コンツェルン代表
Miss Kaguya Sumeragi has arrived!
皇室神楽耶様　ご到着
神楽耶？
Kaguya? What?!
何？
ゼロ！堂々と
Zero! How dare he!
紅蓮のパイロットもいるじゃないか
And that's the Guren pilot
with him, isn't it?
- Who invited him?!
- To a place like this!
誰が招いたのか こんな場所に
He's a terrorist!
テロリストだぞ
これはこれは
Well, well, well!
シュナイゼルやはりあなたが黒幕か
Schneizel! So, you are
the puppet master behind all this!
You're nearly ready to graduate,
aren't you?
単位はあと少しなんでしょ？
あっ そうしたら ね
I suppose
I should finish, huh?
Still, I'm happy for you.
You seem to be doing well for yourself.
でもよかったニーナも元気みたいだし
I'm a little relieved.
なんか安心しちゃった
安心？
Relieved?
うん 困ったことがあったら相談にのるから
If anything happens,
you can come to me for advice.
やめて
Stop that.
私 ミレイちゃんのことは好きよ
Milly, I like you, but I hate women
who have no depth to them.
でも うわべだけの女は嫌い
ユーフェミア様は逃げなかった
Princess Euphemia didn't run away.
命をかけて私を助けてくれた
She risked her life to save me.
ユーフェミア様だけが私を救ってくれたの
Princess Euphemia was
the only one who helped me.
私だって
And I'll help you, too.
口だけの同情ならやめて！
Stop just mouthing sympathy for me!
You always play around, and then
retreat behind Ashford like it's a shield!
ミレイちゃんはいつも遊び気分で
困ったらアッシュフォードという盾を使うのよ
ロイド先生との婚約だってそういうことでしょう
Your engagement to
Dr. Lloyd is just like that!
私をいつも下にみて 保護者の顔をして偽善に浸って
You always look down on me, acting like you're my
guardian while you swim in your own hypocrisy!
もう違うの 私は！
I've changed!
Now acknowledge that!
私を認めなさいよ！
神楽耶！
Kaguya!
貢物がみずからあらわれたのです実に喜ばしい
Our wedding gift has shown up
on its own accord.
What a wonderful thing!
神楽耶もブリタニアへ？
You're giving Kaguya
to Britannia as well?
Forget her.
Her crimes warrant the death penalty.
もう忘れなさい死罪になるべき女子です
おかしいわここはブリタニアではないのに
That's wrong!
This isn't Britannia!
The Black Knights killed Gao Hai.
黒の騎士団はガオハイを殺しています
Just leave the politics to us.
まつりごとはわれわれにおまかせください
今までもそうやってきたではありませんか
Isn't that what you've always done?
でも 友達を
But, she's my friend.
やめませんか 諍いが　本日は祝の席でしょう
Can't we stop this quarrel?
Today is a day of celebration,
is it not?
ですが
But...
Miss Sumeragi, could you please not have
Zero escort you at the wedding tomorrow?
皇さん明日の婚姻の儀では ゼロの同伴をご遠慮いただけますか
Well...
I suppose it can't be helped.
それは 致し方ありませんね
ブリタニアの宰相閣下がおっしゃるなら
If that is what the prime minister
of Britannia says... Withdraw!
引け！
シュナイゼル 目の前に姿をさらしたな
So, Schneizel...
You appear right before me?
さすがに警戒しているか
As watchful as always, I see.
枢さん
Mr. Kururugi?
Do you remember me?
おぼえておいでですかいとこの私を
It's me, your cousin.
あたりまえだろ
Of course I do.
We're the last survivors of
the Six Houses of Kyoto, aren't we?
京都六家の生きのこりは 私たちだけとなりましたね
桐原さんたちはテロの支援者だった
Kirihara and the others
were supporters of terrorists.
死罪はしかたがなかった
Their executions couldn't be helped.
お忘れかしら？
Have you forgotten?
Master Zero once saved your life.
昔 ゼロ様があなたを救ったことを
Do you plan to execute someone
you owe your life to?
その恩人も死罪になさるおつもり？
それとこれとは
That has nothing to do with this!
残念ですわ言の葉だけで人を殺せたらよろしいのに
How sad. If only we could
kill with our words alone.
Prince Schneizel.
シュナイゼル殿下
ひとつ チェスでもいかがですか？
Would you care for
a game of chess?
Oh?
ほう？
私が勝ったら枢木卿をいただきたい
If I win, I'd like to have Sir Kururugi.
神楽耶様にさしあげますよ
I'll give him to Lady Kaguya.
Oh! That would be
a most lovely present!
まあ最高のプレゼントですわ
Enjoy your anticipation
of receiving it.
楽しみにお待ちください
スザクさえいなくなれば
If I can get Suzaku out of here,
I can use my Geass on everyone here.
ここにいる全員にギアスがかけられる
逆転のチェックメイトだ
A checkmate that
would turn everything around.
では私が勝ったら その仮面をはずしてもらうとしようかな
Well then, if I win,
will you remove your helmet for me?
いいでしょう
Very well.
あっはは楽しい余興になりそうだね
This has turned into
a fine evening's entertainment!
せっかくの余興 何も別室にしなくても
Surely we don't have to stay in
a separate room away from the show?
He's playing a terrorist.
Something might happen.
相手はテロリスト何かあってからでは
How absurd.
My husband is the one who will win.
杞憂ですわ勝つのは私の夫ですもの
あっはは気持はわかるが
I understand how you feel,
私には弟のシュナイゼルが負けることなど想像できないよ
but I can't imagine anyone but my
brother Schneizel winning this game.
これが黒の騎士団エース 紅蓮のパイロット
So, this is the ace of the Black
Knights. The pilot of the Guren.
The one from before? She looks a
lot prettier than her wanted poster.
この前のあいつだろ？
手配画像よりずっといいなあ
ああいうのタイプなんだ
Just my type.
強い 殿下が押されている
He's good!
He's pushing in on His Highness!
ほう　まさかきりかえされるとは
Oh? You're fighting back
better than I thought you would.
He's good,
just as I'd expect of my brother.
手ごわい　さすがわが兄上俺が唯一勝てなかった男
He's the only man
I could never beat.
だが それは８年前の話
However, that was eight years ago.
キング
Your king?
If the king doesn't lead, how can he
expect his subordinates to follow?
王から動かないと 部下はついてこないよ
見識だねではこちらも
A fine philosophy! Well, then...
I'll move mine, as well.
これは どちらが勝ってるのかな？
Well, now...
I wonder who's going to win?
They're evenly matched.
互角ですわ
Stubborn competition.
Practically a fight!
意地の張り合い　せめぎあい
どうです？これ以上はすすめないでしょう？
Well? You can't advance
any further, can you?
ふむ このままではスリー フォールド レピティションとなる
At this rate, we'll fall
into a threefold repetition.
私も本意ではないが 引き分けかな？
It wasn't my intention,
but shall we just declare this a draw?
いいや
No.
Hm?
ん？
You'd do well not to underestimate
the white king.
白のキングをあまくみてはいけないな
まさか
You wouldn't!
チェックメイト
Checkmate.
それではゼロが駒をすすめれば
If Zero moves his king...
シュナイゼルの
then he'll...
キングがとられてしまう
...capture Schneizel's king!
ふざけすぎだよ
Oh, that's too big of a joke!
わざと負けるおつもり？
Is he intentionally losing?
なんですか これは
What is this?
Are you just handing me a victory?
拾えといわれるのか 勝利を
この誘いを受けるということは屈服するという意味だ
If I take this invitation,
it means giving in to his plan.
許してはいけないこんな屈辱をうけるなど
I can't allow this!
This humiliation!
皇帝陛下なら 迷わずとっただろうね
The emperor would have taken it
without any hesitations.
君がどういう人間か 少しわかった気がするよ
I've learned just a bit about
what kind of man you really are.
Schneizel!
You dare look down on me like that?!
シュナイゼル！あなたはそうやって見下して！
ゼロ！ユーフェミア様のかたき！
Zero!
Princess Euphemia will be avenged!
Stop it, Nina!
やめるんだ！ニーナ！
どうして邪魔するのよ！
Why are you stopping me?!
スザクはユーフェミア様の騎士だったんでしょう！
You were her knight, weren't you?!
はっそうだ僕は なぜ
That's right. So, why?
You're just an Eleven
after all, aren't you?!
あなたはやっぱりイレヴンなのよ！
Nina!
ニーナ！
Kallen!
You're half-Britannian, so why?!
ナイフあなただって 半分ブリタニアの血をひいてるくせに！
No. I'm Japanese.
違う 私は日本人よ
日本人？イレヴンでしょう？
"Japanese?"
You mean Eleven, right?
イレヴンのくせに 友達の顔をして！
You're an Eleven,
and you dared to act like my friend?!
かえしてよ！ユーフェミア様を！
Give her back to me!
Give back Princess Euphemia!
必要だったのに！
I needed her!
She was a goddess to me!
私の女神さまを！
Nina...
ニーナ
Zero killed her, but you!
ゼロが 殺したのに
これもゼロがひきおこした悲劇
This is just one more
tragedy Zero's caused.
ニーナ
Nina...
ごめんなさい 今まで  でも
I'm sorry about everything
that's happened. But even so...
カレン かわっていないのね あなたは
Kallen...
You haven't changed at all.
ブラックリベリオンの時も私たちのことを気にかけて
Even during the Black Rebellion,
you were worried about us.
Even so, I...
なのに 私は
俺は ひきかえさない！
I can't turn back now!
すまなかったね ゼロ
Forgive me, Zero.
Let's end our little game here.
余興はここまでとしよう
それと確認するが 明日の参列はご遠慮願いたい
Also, I'd like to confirm...
that you will not
attend the ceremony tomorrow.
Next time, a game of
chess won't save you.
次はチェスなどではすまないよ
不安がらないで
Have no fear.
That's right.
Once I'm married to this man tomorrow,
そう 明日私はこの人と婚姻の儀を終えたら
I'll leave the forbidden city
and go to Britannia as a hostage.
朱禁城の外に
ブリタニアへ人質として
こんな形で外にでることになるなんて
I never thought this was how
I would finally go outside.
初めてが終わりになるなんて
It'll be my first and last time.
もう二度と帰ってこられないのね
I'll never return here, will I?
私は 私は
I... I...
我は問う！
We ask this question!
By the voice of heaven, the roar of
the land, and the hearts of the people!
天の声　地の叫び 人の心！
何をもってこの婚姻を中華連邦の意志とするか！
In what way does this marriage represent
the will of the Chinese Federation?!
Terrorists?!
テロリスト？！
ってかクーデターじゃないの？
Don't you mean a coup d'état?!
血迷うたか？シンクー
Have you lost your mind, Xing-ke?!
Silence, Zhao Hao! In the name of the people,
I challenge the legality of this wedding!
黙れ！趙皓！
すべての人民を代表し我はこの婚姻に異議を唱える！
Hold him back!
とりおさえろ！
It's strange.
おかしなものだ
As much as I pray to save
the people who are starving,
餓えた民を救いたいと願いつつも私は天子様のことを考えている
I'm only thinking about
Her Majesty's welfare.
Right now...
今こそ！私は！
I am...
Stop the broadcast!
放送を切れ！
たいへんなことになりま
This is terrible...
Hey! What about the Prez?!
ちょっと 会長は？
神楽耶さま さがりましょう
Lady Kaguya,
let's get out of here.
え なに？
What?
Suzaku!
スザクくん
Right!
わかっています
やめい！ブリタニアの方々にあたったらおおごとよ
Don't shoot! If anything happens to
the Britannians, it'll be disastrous!
Seize him!
とりおさえるのだ！
Traitor! You think
the empress is yours alone?!
不忠なり！天子様を己がものとしようとは
そうだなこの行動が天子様の御心にそっているかどうかわからん
That's right.
I have no idea if this is
what Her Majesty desires.
天子様は６年前のことなど　おぼえておられぬかもしれん
She may not even remember
what happened 6 years ago.
それでも 私は命を救っていただいたかわりに
Even so, I made an eternal promise to
her in return for her sparing my life!
永続調和の契りを交わしたのだ
A vow I swore in my heart!
私の心に誓って
I will take the empress!
To the outside world!
天子さまに 外の世界を！
Xing-ke!
シンクー！
シンクー！シンクー！シンクー！
Xing-ke!
She does... She remembers!
おぼえて おられた
我が心に迷いなし！
In my heart, I have no hesitation!
シンクー！
Xing-ke!
感謝するシンクー
I appreciate this, Xing-ke!
君のおかげで 私も動きやすくなった
You've made it easier for
me to make my move.
Th-That man, too?!
あの男まで
Zero, what's the meaning of this?
ゼロ それはどういう意味だ？
Don't move!
動くな！
卑劣な
How cowardly!
ゼロ あれほど忠告したのに
Zero... Even after I warned you...
I thought the Black Knights owed us
for what we did for them in Area 11.
黒の騎士団にはエリア１１での貸しがあったはずだが
だからこの婚礼をこわしてやる
Which is why
I'm ruining this wedding.
Just as you people wanted.
君たちが望んだとおりに
However, I'm taking
the bride with me!
ただし 花嫁はこの私がもらいうける
シンク
Xing-ke!
Your Majesty!
天子様！
この外道が！
You scum!
Oh, am I?
おや そうかい
Yes. Zero's true objective...
うん ゼロの本当の目的それがここなら厄介だから
If it's here, that could
mean trouble for us.
ああそれで私のために手配を？
Yes. Is that why you've made
preparations for me?
そうだよ
It is.
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
調整さえすめば C.C.もルルーシュも敵ではありません
Once I'm properly adjusted,
C.C. and Lelouch will be no match for me.
このジェレミア ゴットバルト ご期待には全力で
Your expectations of
Jeremiah Gottwald will be met...
With all my strength!
Mune no naka itsuka hirotta
Someday let's try to pick up and rebuild
Shiawase no kakera atsumete miyou
The fragments of happiness in our hearts
Wasurekaketeita melody
That nearly forgotten melody
Iroasezu boku no man'naka ni
Stay vivid, deep inside of me
Arigatou kokoro kara
I thank you from the bottom of my heart
Boku ni ima ga aru no wa minna no okagesa
Everything I have now, I owe to everyone
Arigatou kokoro kara
I thank you from the bottom of my heart
Tsugi wa boku ga minna ni happy okuru yo
Next I'll send happiness to everyone
Nanimokamo wasurenai yo
I won't forget anything
Ano hi no boku mo boku dakara
Because I'm still the same as I was that day
Daisuki da yo'tte itsumo
You need me to keep on saying
Itte agenakya dame da ne
How much I love you
Namida ga kobore sou na nagai yoru wa
On those long nights, your tears about to overflow
Futto furikaette
Just turn around
Ashiato wo tadorun'da
Follow those footprints
Ano hi wo wasurenai you ni
So that you'll never forget that day
天子は我が手に落ちた
Even if they try to move now, it's too late.
皆俺の策で踊るがいい
The empress, the symbol of the Chinese
Federation, has fallen into my hands.
華連邦という国に一気にチェックメイトを決めてやる
Xing-ke, the High Eunuchs, even Schneizel...
そうすれば　あいつに迫る力が手に入る
Let them all dance to my plan!
そのためなら　俺は
I'm through positioning my pieces.
This is no game of chess.
ゼロ中華連邦までこわすつもりなのか
I'm going for a checkmate of the nation
known as the Chinese Federation!
見るがいい私の遠大な計画を
And once I have,
I'm coming for him!
ところでスザクほかにやるべきことがあるのではないかなあ
I'll have the power to approach
the emperor of Britannia!
And for that, I swear, I'll!
くっそうだった
特別プレゼントのお知らせです
WHEN SHEN HU WINS GLORY
万代から好評発売中のプラモデル　ランスロット　エアキャヴァルリーと紅蓮弐式そしてヴィンセントをセットで
十名様にプレゼントします
パスワードを入力してご覧の携帯サイトから応募してくれたまえ
今から一時間の限定受付だ
特製待受けもゲットせよ
僕は必ずおまえをとめる
世界は私が変えて見せよ
だから　諸君　また来週